NumPy is short for Numerical Python and is
NumPY 是 Numerical Python 的缩写
a library designed for efficient Scientific Computation.
其实就是一个库 用于高效的科学计算
It's built on top of the programming language C,
其底层代码是 C 编程语言
which works at a lower level on our computer.
该语言为计算机的底层代码
To understand what this means for the speed of our code,
想知道这对提高代码速度有何意义
see the link in the instructor notes.
请查看讲师注释里的链接
At the core of NumPy,
NumPy 的核心
is its N-dimensional array object.
是 N 维数组对象
This is just a multi-dimensional array that
该对象本质是一个多维数列
holds a group of elements that all have the same data type.
由一组具备相同数据类型的元素组成
In other words, it's like a grid that can take on
换句话说 这个数列有点像一个网格
many shapes and enforces every element in that grid to have the same type,
网格可以有多种形状 会使其内的所有元素保持相同的类型
whether that's string, float,
无论是字符串、浮点数
boolean, or something else.
布尔值等 都是如此
Making arrays only able to hold one data type at a time
这种让数组一次只能容纳一种数据类型的特性
helps NumPy make very quick computations with vector operations.
允许 NumPy 可以进行向量运算 因而 NumPy 的计算速度很快
These arrays, along with many useful functions in NumPy,
这些数组加上许多实用的 NumPy 函数
can significantly optimize and simplify operations on data.
大幅优化并简化了数据操作
Here's a simple example that demonstrates this.
举个简单的例子
First, let's import NumPy with the standard alias for this library, NP.
首先 用标准缩写 np 导入 NumPy
This generates an array of 100 million floats between zero and one.
这会生成一个数组 数组由 1 亿个在 0 和 1 之间的浮点数组成
Let's compare the time it takes playing Python
我们来比较 Python
versus NumPy to calculate the mean of this array.
和 NumPy 计算该数组平均数的耗时
Instead of Python, we do this by getting the sum of
用 Python 求平均数
X and dividing that by the length of X, pretty straightforward.
我们可以先求 x 的总和 然后将其除以 x 的长度 很简单吧
Using the time package,
使用包 time
we can check how long this line of code takes to run.
我们可以查看这段代码的运行时长
That took about 9.3 seconds.
大概是 9.3 秒
Makes sense that it took a while with 100 million values.
毕竟有 1 亿个值 这么久也不奇怪
Now, let's see how long it takes NumPy.
现在来看 NumPy 需要多久
That was ridiculously faster.
简直快得不可思议
NumPy took only 0.092 seconds,
NumPy 只花了 0.092 秒
while plain Python took 9.31.
而纯 Python 花了 9.31 秒
As you saw, NumPy can make a difference of orders of magnitude in computation time.
正如你所见 NumPy 在计算速度上有着数量级的优势
Imagine how much this speeds up the process for
想象一下
more complex situations that require many more calculations.
如果遇到更复杂的情况 需要更大的计算量 NumPy 能提高多少效率啊
For example, let's say we're engineering a whole new feature or column in a dataset,
假设我们要在数据集里求一个新特征 也就是要新建一列
which you compute by multiplying the values and two columns
你需要计算两列的乘积
together and dividing that by the values in another for each row.
再将乘积除以另一列每行的值
Unlike NumPy, plain Python would require
不像 NumPy
a massively long loop through all of
纯 Python 需要用一个非常长的循环
the rows to compute the new value for each individual row.
才能遍历所有行 计算出每一行的新值
In many machine learning problems,
很多机器学习问题
you'll often find yourself using NumPy arrays in many situations.
有很多场合都要使用 NumPy 数组
For instance, you might use a NumPy array to hold
比如 你可能会用 NumPy 数组
the pixel values of an image that will be fed into a model for image classification.
来存放某个图像的像素值 以便将其传递给图像分类模型
Later, we'll also learn about a popular data science package,
稍后我们还会介绍一个常用的数据科学包 Pandas
Pandas, which is very useful for manipulating datasets.
这个包很擅长处理数据集
It's actually built on top of NumPy,
实际上 Pandas 的底层用了 NumPy
which is why its computations are so fast.
这是它计算速度那么快的秘诀
Now that you've learned a bit about the power of NumPy, let's get started.
既然你已经初步了解 NumPy 的威力了 让我们正式开始吧